Samuel N. Morarescu

Stavanger, Norway

Date of birth: 1st of February 1989

Tel: (+47) 96 87 49 28

E-mail: samueln.morarescu@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>link</u>

Driving licence: B category



PROFILE

I am interested to apply for a position of Junior Web Developer in Stavanger Area. My experience of 5 years in the IT Department helped me gain relevant IT knowledge within programming, operating systems, teaching environment, multimedia, web / interaction design.

I am keen to be part of the digitalization and innovation processes. I work effectively in teams as this helps to share experience and knowledge and get superior results in a synergistic manner for the assigned projects. I'm on the process of learning how to code more efficiently and finding solutions to problems by attending the Mentored Online Full Stack Bootcamp offered by Code Institute Ltd Dublin, Ireland.

EDUCATION:

Aug 2018/2019: Full Stack Software Development Diploma (Online Bootcamp), Code Institute, Dublin, Ireland

- HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Data Visualization(with D3.js, Crossfilter.js, DC.js, Queue.js),Python, Github, Data Management, Agile Development, Frameworks (Django)

Feb 2018: Dark Web - Dark Markets - training CEPOL

2017-2018: Web Design "Master Courses" - Web Design Level I & II, JavaScript, SEO, PHP, Bootstrap

2017: **HTML course Level** I Crystal Mind Academy

2014 : CISCO CCNA I

2013: CISCO - IT Essentials

2008-2011: Police Academy "Alexandru Ioan Cuza", Bucharest, Romania Study of Law & Public Order, Bachelor's Degree

2004 – 2008 : High School " Voievodul Mircea", Târgoviște, Romania; Mathematics –Computer Science Intensive; Baccalaureate diploma

EXPERIENCE:

2013 - August 2018 : Specialist Officer III at Police Academy "Alexandru Ioan Cuza", Bucharest, website admin of: http://www.academiadepolitie.ro/index.html

- Offering IT&C support for the employees working in the Police Academy, repair, maintenance, installing and configuring computers that have errors;
- Installing and configuring Windows (XP SP3, 7 PRO/Enterprise, 8.1PRO; 10.1 PRO) based computers and joining them in the domain.
- Installing and administrating servers with Windows Server 2012;
- Administrating, design and maintenance of the official website and other subsidiaries websites, checking for missing content, broken links, creating new pages and responsive design.
- Offering assistance and helping with all IT&C related problems in the annual admission process and other events that take place in the Police Academy;
- Installed and configured the e-learning platform based on open source software moodle.
- Installed and configured the security information policies according to the National Registry Office for Classified Information;
- Decrypted several computers with Kaspersky Anti-Ransomware Tool and restored data from the infected computers in the Police Academy;

2012-2013 Police Officer IV Law Enforcement Officer for the Romanian Police Force

LANGUAGES

- Mother language: Romanian

	Understanding				Speaking				Writing	
	Listening		Reading		Spoken interaction		Spoken production			
English	C2	Proficient user	C2	Proficient user	C1	Proficient user	C1	Proficient user	C1	Proficient user
French	B1	Independent user	B1	Independent user	A1	Basic User	A1	Basic User	A1	Basic User
Norwegian	A2	Basic User	A2	Basic User	A1	Basic User	A1	Basic User	A1	Basic User

SKILLS:

Soft skills: Leadership and effective communication skills gained through my experience as a police officer and as being part of the support IT&C Department in the Police Academy in Bucharest.

Job related skills: Understanding and using security tools in the IT domain;

Navigating through the web from the security point of view. This skill was learned from circumstances that arose when some users got infected with ransomware worm or were victims of a phishing attack and info had to be recovered, where possible, especially their documents.

UX understanding: As a programmer, it is important to put oneself into the user shoes and make the experience relevant and pleasant for him.

Digital skills: The following knowledge was acquired during work at the Department of IT&C, education and from personal researching:

- Good knowledge of using Hiren's Boot; Good command of Adobe Dreamweaver;
- Good knowledge of installing and configuring Trend Micro OfficeScan;
- Basic knowledge of installing and configuring an eLearning machine with moodle;
- Configuring Outlook and working with the Office Suite; Basic knowledge of the photo editing software GIMP;

INTERESTS & ADDITIONAL INFORMATION:

Hiking, running, reading, meditation

PORTFOLIO:

Projects Repositories: https://github.com/Walachul
Live websites: https://walachul.github.io/ucd-resume/

https://walachul.github.io/CostinDudescu_MilestoneProject/

https://walachul.github.io/HarmoniSenter/

https://walachul.github.io/Analysis Carbon Dioxide Worldwide/

REFERENCES:

- Cătălin Doroș Chief IT Bureau, Police Academy, Bucharest, catalin.doros@academiadepolitie.ro
- Lucian Mircea IT Specialist Officer, Police Academy, Bucharest, lucian.mircea@academiadepolitie.ro